incomeschool.com 2019-06-20

# Privacy Policy | Income School

## Who we are

Our website address is: https://incomeschool.com.  This site is owned an operated by Income School LLC, a limited liability company in the state of Idaho in the United States.  We can be reached at [privacy@incomeschool.com](mailto:privacy@incomeschool.com).

## What personal data we collect and why we collect it

### Comments

When visitors leave comments on the site we collect the data shown in the comments form, and also the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection.

An anonymized string created from your email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the Gravatar service to see if you are using it. The Gravatar service privacy policy is available here: https://automattic.com/privacy/. After approval of your comment, your profile picture is visible to the public in the context of your comment.

We do not collect your email address from the comments form for use in any email list, such as a newsletter or marketing email list.  We also never sell email addresses to third parties.

### Media

In general, users are not able to upload images or other media files to this website.  However, if you do upload images to the website, you should avoid uploading images with embedded location data (EXIF GPS) included. Visitors to the website can download and extract any location data from images on the website.

### Contact forms

When you fill out a contact form on IncomeSchool.com we only collect the information you enter into the contact form.  If the form asks for your name, email address, or any other personal information, then that information is sent to us via email.  We only retain that information—including your email address—for as long as necessary to address your purpose in contacting us.

Email addresses provided in contact forms are not ever used by Income School LLC for any purpose other than to reply to you in regards to your reason for contacting us.  We never sell information from contact forms to any third parties for any purpose.

### Cookies

If you leave a comment on our site you may opt-in to saving your name, email address and website in cookies. These are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment. These cookies will last for one year.

If you have an account and you log in to this site, we will set a temporary cookie to determine if your browser accepts cookies. This cookie contains no personal data and is discarded when you close your browser.

When you log in, we will also set up several cookies to save your login information and your screen display choices. Login cookies last for two days, and screen options cookies last for a year. If you select “Remember Me”, your login will persist for two weeks. If you log out of your account, the login cookies will be removed.

If you edit or publish an article, an additional cookie will be saved in your browser. This cookie includes no personal data and simply indicates the post ID of the article you just edited. It expires after 1 day.

### Embedded content from other websites

Articles on this site may include embedded content (e.g. videos, images, articles, etc.). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website.

These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracing your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.

### Analytics

As you use this Website, we use automatic data collection technology (Google Analytics) to collect certain information about your device, browsing actions, and patterns. This generally includes information about where you are, how you use our website, and any communications between your computer and this site. Among other things, we will collect data about the type of computer you use, your Internet connection, your IP address, your operating system, and your browser type.

We collect this data for statistical purposes and we don’t collect personal information _._  The purpose of this data is to improve our Website and offerings.

If you wish to opt out of Google Analytics so that none of your personal information is collected and stored by Google Analytics, you can [download and install the Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on here](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout).  For more information on how Google collects and uses your data, you can [access the Google Privacy Policy here](https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en).

## Who we share your data with

We don’t sell or share your data with anyone.  We do use a 3rd party email provider to store your email address if you voluntarily signed up for our email newsletter.  The privacy policy for [SendInBlue can be found here](https://www.sendinblue.com/legal/privacypolicy/).  We also use third party software for our course platform and membership access.

## LearnDash LMS

We collect information about you during the course purchase process (PayPal and Stripe), as well as information relating to your course progression.

#### What we collect and store

When you purchase from us, we’ll ask you to provide email address. We’ll use this information for purposes, such as, to:

  * Send you information about your account and order
  * Create your account for our LMS

If you register a free account then we will store your email address.

We store information about you for as long as your account exists.

We store course progress, including completion status, quiz scores, assignments and/or essay submissions (if applicable).

We will also store comments on courses, lessons, topics, assignments, and essays if you choose to leave them.

#### Who on our team has access

Members of our team have access to the information you provide us. For example, both Administrators and Group Leaders can access:

  * Order information such as your enrolled courses, course progress and username / email address.

Any additional information added in your WordPress User Profile can also be visible to the administrator(s).

#### Payments

We accept payments through PayPal. When processing payments, some of your data will be passed to PayPal, including information required to process or support the payment, such as the purchase total and billing information.

Please see the [PayPal Privacy Policy](https://www.paypal.com/us/webapps/mpp/ua/privacy-full)  and the [Stripe Privacy Policy](https://stripe.com/us/privacy) for more details.

## How long we retain your data

If you leave a comment, the comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely. This is so we can recognize and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue.

For users that register on our website (if any), we also store the personal information they provide in their user profile. All users can see, edit, or delete their personal information at any time (except they cannot change their username). Website administrators can also see and edit that information.

## What rights you have over your data

If you have an account on this site, or have left comments, you can request to receive an exported file of the personal data we hold about you, including any data you have provided to us. You can also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you. This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes.

## Where we send your data

Visitor comments may be checked through an automated spam detection service.

## Our contact information

For questions regarding your data and how we use it, you can reach us at [privacy@incomeschool.com](mailto:privacy@incomeschool.com).  You can also email us here if you would like an extract of all of your personal information stored on our website or to request that we delete all of your information stored on our website.

## Additional information

### How we protect your data

Income School LLC uses secure third party software such as [MemberPress](https://memberpress.com/privacy/) and [SendOwl](https://www.sendowl.com/privacy) for all financial transactions.  No financial data is collected or stored by Income School LLC.  Their privacy policies can be accessed at the links above.
